HÉLIO ANTÔNIO BORGES JUNIOR

Full Stack Rails Developer

helio.borgesjr@gmail.com | +55 62 992484169 Goiânia – GO, Brazil

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have worked with Ruby on Rails since 2008, leading many projects (administrative systems) in the public sector in Brazil. I own a company that sells courses for banking certifications. I am married and have a little baby girl.

I am enthusiastic about learning new technologies. Skilled in working under pressure and finding solutions to challenges.

I adapt to any working environment and contribute to their existing culture.

SKILLS

- Full Stack Web Development
- Software Engineering

- Team Leader
- Customer Support Expert

WORK HISTORY

CO-Owner | Cassol Borges Training - 01/2019 - Current

- Full Stack Development in Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS, JavaScript for our website, automated routines and reports.
- Customer Support. Digital Marketing, Sales and Commercial Representative.
- Product and Brand Development.

Senior Team Leader Full Stack Dev in Rails | SIEDOS – Goiânia – GO, Brazil 08/2010 – 12/2018

- Led a team of 2-5 members developing administrative systems for a few public institutions in Brazil, specially the Justice Department in our state, Goiás (MPGO).
- Full Stack development in Rails, PostgreSQL, Oracle, HTML, Bootstrap, JavaScript and Flex.
- Experience in Software Engineering. Gathered and defined customer requirements to develop clear specifications for projects.
- Interacted directly with the institution's Executives and Directors to identify, adapt and deliver customer needs.
- Worked within tight deadlines and fast-paced atmosphere.
- Responsible for recruiting, hiring and training team members.

Full Stack Rails Developer | INBRATECH - Goiânia - GO, Brazil 12/2009 - 08/2010

- Full Stack Development in Rails, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Collaborated on stages of systems development lifecycle from requirement gathering to production releases.

Intern Rails Developer | TRE-GO: Regional Electoral Court of Goiás - Goiânia - GO, Brazil 03/2008 - 12/2009

- Full Stack Development in Rails, Oracle, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to current and new projects.
- Maintained systems and helped customers with their problems.

EDUCATION

IPOG - Graduate Institute - Goiânia, GO - 01/2018

MBA: Governance in I.T.

Pontifical Catholic University of Goiás, PUC-GO - 12/2009

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

LANGUAGES

Portuguese and English